Gaurav Kumar

Email: gauravkumar28051997@gmail.com

Phone: 8700759603

Current Address: RZF-338, GALI NO-22 SADH NAGAR

PALAM COLONY, NEW DELHI, PIN-110045

Website: Gaurav Kumar

GIT-HUB: https://github.com/gauravkumar-tech



Summary

Software Developer

- IT Professional with 2+ years of Experience in Software Development. Hands on experience with MicroServices, SpringBoot 5, Java JDK 1.8, Angular 9, Reactis, OracleDB 11g, Spring.
- For More Projects Please Visit: https://github.com/gauravkumar-tech

Professional Summary

- Designing, building and maintaining Java-based applications.
- Contributing and taking part in software and architectural development activities.
- Developing well-designed, efficient, and testable code.
- Conducting software analysis, programming, testing, and debugging.
- Troubleshooting and resolving the reported issues and replying to queries in a timely manner.
- Preparing and producing releases of software components.
- Producing detailed design documentation.
- Improve the code quality by implementing best practices.
- Recommending changes to improve established java application processes.
- Involved in building and deployment of the application in a Linux environment.

| Programming Languages | Java 7,8 |
|--|--|
| Frameworks - Back End | Hibernate 5 with JPA, Spring 5.0 (Core/IOC, MVC, DAO, REST, Boot, Security) Micro Services, Log4J |
| RDBMS Applications | MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL |
| Software Development Processes (SDLC) | Agile |
| Design Patterns | Singleton, Model View Controller (MVC), Data Transfer Object (DTO), Data Access Object (DAO) and Factory Pattern |
| Web Servers | Apache Tomcat 8.0 |
| Version Control System | Git with GitHub |
| Build Automation Tool | Maven |
| Other Tools | Eclipse, Visual Studio Code, STS, MS SQL Server, MySQL Workbench, MS Office (Word, Excel & PowerPoint), Toad |

Projects Worked on: 10+

Project Details

 It's an Enterprise resource planning (ERP) Application containing Sub modules: Admin, Inventory and Financial, Exam, Biometrics, salary Processing which is a service-oriented architecture.

CmpusLynx Software

Name : (CmpusLynx) University ERP Software.

O.S : Windows, Linux

Environment : Spring, Hibernate, Maven, JS, Bootstrap, CSS Server : Apache Tomcat. (Deployment) JBoss Server 8

Database : Oracle

Report Generation : Jasper Report, Apache POI for generate excel sheet report

Role : Developer

Team Size : 9

Duration : 2021 to 2022 (FEB)

Responsibilities:

Coding the front-end with Angular, developing the Controller class and service implementation classes using Java and establishing interaction with databases using Hibernate.

Used JavaScript for Validation of user inputs at the front end.

Involved in understanding client requirements, and implementing it into software.

Involved full time to participate in project team activities.

Involved in the full process of coding, like frontend to backend.

Worked with users to ensure the project meets business needs.

| Front End Technologies | HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Angular 9 |
|------------------------|---|
| Back End Technologies | Java 1.8, Oracle, Spring Boot 5 |
| RDBMS Application | TOAD |
| Tools Used | Spring Tool Suite 4, Eclipse, Vs code, Toad and Postman |
| Duration | 2021 - 2022 (FEB) |

Work Experiences

2 Years, 2 Months, 23 Days

February 2020 - February 2021 (1 Year) (Full Stack Developer)

JSpiders Software Development Training & Placement Institute.
 A 29 Sector 3, 2nd Floor, Noida, Uttar Pradesh 201301, India.

February 2021 - February 2022 (1 Year, 15 days) (Full Stack Developer)

JIL Information Technology Limited
 64/4, Sahibabad Industrial Area Site 4, Sahibabad, Ghaziabad, Uttar Pradesh 201010

February 2022 - March 2022 (1 Month, 8 Days) (Full Stack Developer)

EisenVault Document Management System India
 4th Floor,, Statesman House, Minto Road Complex, Barakhamba, New Delhi, Delhi 110001

March 2022 - Present (1 Month and counting) (Full Stack Developer)

Traqiq Solutions Private Limited
 Noida, Uttar Pradesh 201303, Sector 127, Logix TechnoPark Tower D

Qualification

Technical

 $\underline{\text{B.Tech in Mechanical and A}} \textbf{utomation Engineering, Secured CGPA 6.84, from I.P. University in}$

2020, New Delhi, India.

Higher Secondary $\underline{12}$ $\underline{\text{h}}$ (Science) Secured 65.4% from Shiv vani model Sr. sec. school in 2015, New Delhi (Dwarka), India.

Secondary

10thSecured 65.4% from Shiv vani model Sr. sec. school in 2015, New Delhi (Dwarka), India.

Personal Details

Date of Birth : 28.05.1997

Nationality : Indian

Father's Name : Amber Kumar

Mother's Name : Asha Rani

Languages known : English, Hindi and Punjabi

Marital Status : Single

Interest & Hobbies: Exercising, Bike Riding, Meditation.

Declaration

I do hereby declare that the above information given here are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Place: New Delhi Name: Gaurav Kumar

Date: 15th Apr 2022 (Signature)

gaurav